애니
대니엘입니다
메시지를 남기세요
This is Danielle.
Leave a message.
Hello, again.
안녕, 또 나야
떠나기 전에
얘기 나누고 싶었는데
I was hoping to talk to you
before I left town.
물어보고 싶은 게
숱하게 많을 거야
I know you have
a million questions.
그래서 전화했어
몇 가지 알려주려고
So here I am,
giving you the skinny.
I can't give you
too many details, of course,
물론 아주 상세하게
알려줄 순 없지만
but I can tell you enough
to give you the gist.
내가 하는 일의 대강은
알 수 있을 거야
For starters,
우선은...
내가 하는 일은
what I do is not like what
you see in the movies.
영화에서
보는 것하곤 달라
관광지로 유명한
이곳에서 머문 지도
I've been in a place
for over a week now
that's famous
for its sightseeing,
벌써 일주일째지만
호텔에 틀어박혀 기다리는
시간이 대부분이야
and I've mostly been stuck
in my hotel room, waiting.
I do a lot of waiting,
actually.
기다리는 시간이
정말 길어
Give my love
to the girls.
조카들에게
안부 전해줘
I'll call you back later.
또 연락할게
실례합니다
오페라 하우스 가는 길
혹시 알고 계세요?
"라 트라비아타"를
보고 싶어서요
너무 늦으셨군요
비올레타에 어울리는 배우는
마리아 칼라스뿐이죠
저희 이모는 레나 스코트가
낫다고 하시던데요
Aah!
Oh!
It's okay.
전 괜찮아요
영자막 elderman
www.addic7ed.com
♪ Covert Affairs 02x11 ♪
The Wake-Up Bomb
Original Air Date on November 1, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪
♪ Can you save me ♪
♪ from this nothing
I've become? ♪
♪ it's just something
that I've done ♪
Season 2 Episode 11
The Wake-Up Bomb
♪ I never meant
to cause you worry ♪
♪ don't you blame me ♪
♪ for this nothing
I've become ♪
♪ it's just something
that I've done ♪
한글번역 에렝아이
디시인사이드 기미갤
♪ I never meant to show you
my mistakes ♪
Milk,
two sugars.
우유에 설탕 둘
맞죠?
How do you
always know it's me?
어떻게 항상
나인지 알아요?
육감이라고 부르는
사람들도 있지만
Some people say
it's a sixth sense.
나만은 오감이라고
하고 싶군요
I like to call it a fifth,
but that's just me.
잠깐, 어쩌다
다친 거예요?
Hey, you want to talk
about that injury?
내 기억보다 완력이
20%는 약해졌군요
Your arm feels about 20% weaker
than I remember,
움찔하는 것도
느껴지는데요?
and I detected a wince.
근육이 조금 결려서요
난 괜찮아요
It's just a muscle pull.
I'm fine.
Really.
정말이에요
Mm-hmm.
그 봉투를 꼭 붙들고
있었다고요, 오기
I had that package
in my grasp, Auggie.
손가락에서 빠져나가는
느낌이 아직도 생생해요
I can still feel it
slipping through my fingers.
애니, 그런 일도
있는 법이에요
Annie,
these things happen.
나한텐 아니었죠
Not to me.
연달아 실패를
맛보는 기분이에요
It seems like I'm on a bit
of a losing streak.
좋아요... 자신을
채찍질하는 이유가
Okay,
this self-flagellation--
봉투 때문이에요?
아니면 언니분 때문이에요?
is this about the package
or your sister?
Oh, things with Danielle
are fine.
언니와는 괜찮아요
- 그래요?
- 네
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
언니가 내 전화를
받아주기만 한다면
I think she will let me
move back into the house
집으로 다시 들여보내 주도록
설득할 수도 있어요
if I can just get her
to answer her phone.
- 안녕하세요, 제이
- 네
- Hey, Jai.
- Hey.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
그렇죠
내가 얼마나
눈 밖에 났는지
I've fallen
so far out of favor
even Jai can sense it.
제이도 벌써
아는 모양이네요
제이는 제이 나름의
문제가 있어요
Jai's got troubles of his own,
and you're not out of favor.
당신이 눈 밖에
난 것도 아니에요
타율 10할은 아무도 없어요
조안도 그걸 잘 알죠
Nobody bats 1.000 around here.
Joan knows that.
Okay.
- 알았어요
- 그래도!
But she did ask to see you
in her office
당신이 돌아오는 즉시
사무실로 데려오라고
말하긴 했어요
the second you got back.
You wanted to see me?
부르셨다고요?
Yes. That bag
that you lost--
맞아
잃어버린 가방에 우리가
걱정해야 할 물건 있어?
was there anything inside it
we need to be concerned about?
아뇨, 목록은
이미 제출했는데
No. Uh, I already submitted
the inventory--
현금 약간과
허위 여행 계획서뿐이에요
just some cash
and a phony travel itinerary.
좋아, 잘됐네
Okay, great.
Thanks, Annie.
수고했어, 애니
그 일 때문에
부르신 건가요?
Was that all you wanted
to see me about?
- 그게 다야
- 그 일에 대해서...
- That's all.
- About what happened...
어떻게 행동해야 했었는지
생각을 많이 해봤는데...
I've been thinking a lot
about it
and what I could've done
differently--
괜찮아, 필요했던 정보는
다른 경로를 통해 확보했어
It's okay.
We already got the information
we needed from another source.
- Another source?
다른 경로요?
이러려고 우리가 중복적인
체계를 구축한 거지
That's why we build redundancy
into the system--
계획대로 일이 진행되지 않을
경우를 대비해서 말이야
in case things don't go
according to plan.
I see.
그렇군요
그럼 다음 임무는 뭐죠?
Uh, so what next?
Nothing just yet.
아직 없어
재충전의 시간으로
삼는 게 좋을 거야
You should take this opportunity
to recharge your batteries.
That's not necessary.
그럴 필요 없는데요
이 악문다고 점수
따는 거 아냐, 애니
You don't get bonus points
for a stiff upper lip, Annie.
Go home and rest up.
집에 가서
좀 쉬어
그래서요?
So?
그래서 수고했대요
So she said, "good job,"
and sent me home to rest up.
쉬라고 집에
보내줬어요
많은 의미를 부여하지
않으려 하고 있어요
I'm gonna try and not read
too much into that.
하지 마요
다친 데나 신경 써요
Don't. Go take care
of your wince.
You have some place
to stay?
머물 곳은 있어요?
You mean
besides Joan's doghouse?
조안의 개집 말고요?
Annie.
애니...
당신이 그동안 안전 가옥을
마련하라고 했었죠?
You know
how you keep telling me
to set up a safe house?
- Yeah.
그랬죠
결국 그렇게 됐네요
Well,
it's finally happened.
오늘 임대 계약서에
서명할 거예요
I sign
the lease tonight.
♬ Kill Your Heroes ♬
AWOLNATION
- 언니!
- 안녕?
- Hi!
- Oh, hey.
I didn't know
if you'd be back yet.
- 돌아온 지 몰랐어
- 오늘 아침에 왔어
I got back this morning.
지낼 곳은
찾았으면 싶은데?
So you found a place
to stay, I hope.
I did, yes.
응, 찾았어
그래... 잘됐다
Good.
Um, I'm--I'm glad.
I'm glad you're glad.
언니가 그렇다니
나도 기뻐
Uh, hey, I know
it's movie night tonight.
오늘 영화 보는 날이지?
지난 주에 뭐 볼까
조카들한테...
I told the girls last week
that we could watch, um--
저기 그게...
다른 게 아니라
Uh, listen, you know, I need
you to, um, move your stuff
별채에 있는 내 짐
가져가라고 전화한 거야
out of the guesthouse.
I'm gonna be showing it
to a few potential tenants.
세들 사람들한테
보여줄 생각이거든
그래... 알았어
Sure, uh, I understand.
I can come by right now,
if you want.
- 언니 괜찮으면 지금 갈까?
- 오늘은 좀 곤란한데
Yeah.
No, tonight's not good.
But, uh, before the end
of the week, okay?
이번 주 지나기
전까지는 되지?
- 알았어
- 그래, 끊어
- Okay.
- Okay, bye.
이봐, 캠
잠깐만
Hey, Cam, wait up.
자꾸 물어봐도 이번 달엔
포커 주최 안 할 거야
You were asking me
about poker this month.
I'm not hosting.
Ah, don't worry about that.
그건 됐어
잘됐군, 지난번 일로
아내가 아직도 잔소리야
Good. My wife's still
on my ass about the last time.
I need to know where
the intelligence committee is
정보위원회의 정보 누설 조사
진행 상황을 알고 싶어
on the leak investigation.
안 되는 거 알잖아
You know
I can't divulge that,
사교클럽 형제한테도
마찬가지야
not even
for an old fraternity brother.
상세한 건 필요 없어
I don't need details,
just a top-level view.
대략적인 것만이라도
We're shutting down
the investigation,
이번 주로
조사를 종결할 거야
end of this week.
종결한다고?
Shutting it down?
맞아, 입 단속 못하는
CIA를 위해서지
Yeah, for an agency
that reportedly can't keep
its mouth shut,
더는 진술하려는
사람이 없어
no one seems to want
to tell us anything.
내가 말할게
Well,
I want to tell you something.
더는 증언을
듣지 않을 예정이야
We're not taking
any more depositions.
My boss thinks the whole thing
is toxic.
내 상관은 이 일을
유해하다고 생각해
- 그만 덮고 싶어해
- 날 소환해
- He wants to put it behind him.
- Call me in.
내 말은 들을 가치가
있을 거라고 장담하지
I swear it will be worth
the committee's time
to hear what
I have to say.
네가 DPD에서
안 좋다는 얘기 들었어
I hear you're getting stymied
in the D.P.D.,
아서가 널 억지로 피닉스로
보낸다는데, 사실이야?
that Arthur's threatening
to farm you out to Phoenix.
Is that true?
- 그게 무슨 상관인데?
- 내 지위가 걸린 일이야
What does that have to do
with anything?
I'm just saying,
it's my rep on the line here.
뭔가 다른 속셈으로
증언한다면...
So, if you're coming in because
you got an ax to grind--
내가 아는 건
아주 결정적인 거야
I know where the bodies
are buried on this one, Cam,
누구 짓인지도
알고 있지
and who did the shoveling.
I can name names.
이름을 댈 수 있어
Trust me.
날 믿어
Etxarte
에차르떼
맘에 들어요?
You like?
Mm. I do...
Very much so.
네, 정말 맘에 들어요
읽고 계시는 책은
괜찮나요?
That book
you're reading...
Is it good?
Not particularly, no.
특별히 좋진 않아요
Great.
Then, uh...
그럼... 오늘밤
말동무를 부탁드려도
If I ask you
to keep me company tonight,
손해 보실 건 없겠군요
you won't be
missing anything.
엑사르떼?
Ex-arte?
'에차르떼'요
'엑스'보단 '츠'에 가깝죠
Et-sharte.
More "sh" than "ex."
Etxarte.
에차르떼
훌륭해요
Bueno. And you said
you don't speak any Basque.
바스크어 모르는 거
정말 맞아요?
무슨 뜻이죠?
What does it mean?
It's the name
of my family.
우리 가족의 성(姓)이에요
흔한 이름이죠
It's very common there.
Etxe in Basque means home.
에체는 바스크어로
집이란 뜻이에요
아르떼는 '사이'죠
Arte, between.
"A home between."
"집 사이"
여기나 저기라고
할 수 없는 장소죠
Like a place
neither here nor there.
집처럼 편안한 곳
같이요?
Like a home
away from home.
Yes, like a home
맞아요, 집처럼
편안한 곳이요
맘에 드네요
I like this.
여기 모두가
어딘가에서 왔거나
Everybody here is either
from someplace else
or on their way
to someplace else.
어디론가 가는 중이죠
그 점이 우릴
무척 고독하게 해요
It can make us feel very alone
in the world.
집이라 부를 곳이
필요해지죠
You need a place
that you can call home,
식당이라 할지라도요
even if it's only
a restaurant.
Does what I say
make any sense to you?
조금이라도
이해가 가나요?
Yeah.
네
당신의 언어 감각을
알아볼 수 있어요
I can tell you're good
with languages.
It's your lips.
입술을 보면 알죠
굉장히 유연한
입을 가졌군요
You have
a very supple mouth.
Does my directness
embarrass you?
너무 직설적이라
불편하신가요?
당신 같은 남자를 조심하라고
어머니가 말씀하셨죠
My mother told me to
be careful with men like you.
One of those
bad-boy chefs, right?
"나쁜 남자" 스타일의
요리사군요?
요리사는 전부
나쁜 남자예요
All chefs are bad boys.
We play with knives and fire.
칼이랑 불을
가지고 놀고
We stay up all night.
We drink way too much.
밤새 일어나 있고...
술도 엄청 마시죠
문신이나
자존심도 있죠
The tattoos, the ego...
미인을 주변에 두고
싶어하는 것도 있죠
And we like to surround
ourselves with beauty.
Oh, I didn't realize how late
it was getting. I should go.
이렇게 늦었는지 몰랐네요
이만 가볼게요
안 돼요, 디저트는
드시고 가셔야죠
No, no, no, no, no.
You must stay for dessert--
아몬드와 체리 타트예요
almond and cherry tart.
제가 과수원에서
직접 따서 가져온 체리예요
The cherries I fly in
from an orchard
제 고향집 근처
강변에 있는 과수원이죠
down the river
from my childhood home.
It looks fantastic.
근사해 보이네요
이자라와
함께 드셔야죠
And you must have some Izarra
to go with it.
Uh, I don't know.
Um--
글쎄요...
체리엔 이자라가 필수예요
You can't have cherry tart
without Izarra.
제가 함께 하죠
I will share it with you.
체리를 처음 맛본
순간을 기억하나요?
Do you remember the first time
you tasted cherry?
I don't know.
아뇨
Close your eyes.
눈을 감아요
맛이 기억을
이끌어낼 거예요
Let the taste
transport you.
Mmm.
Buenos dias.
좋은 아침이에요
Uh, buenos dias.
좋은... 아침
얘는 거스예요
당신을 좋아하네요
This is Gus.
He likes you.
사람 보는 눈이
탁월하답니다
He's a good judge
of character.
여기요, 드세요
Here, eat.
Uh, I'm not hungry.
What time is it?
배고프지 않아요
지금 몇 시죠?
It's a quarter to 6:00.
6시 15분 전이에요
I'm late already
for the fish market.
어시장 가기에
조금 늦었네요
Oh, okay.
그렇군요...
당신은 머물러
있어도 돼요
It's okay for you
to stay.
언제든 가고 싶을 때
가시면 됩니다
You can leave
whenever you like.
Thank you, Zavier.
That's very kind of you.
고마워요, 자비에르
정말 친절하시네요
Um, I don't mean to sound like
an ungrateful hungover floozy,
감사할 줄도 모르는
싸구려 술꾼 여자처럼
말하고 싶진 않지만
but what am I doing here?
제가 왜 여기에
와 있는 거죠?
- You don't remember?
- Not really.
기억 안 나요?
잘 안 나네요
It must have been
the Izarra.
틀림없이...
이자라 때문이겠군요
아, 이자라... 네
Oh, the Izarra.
Yeah, yeah.
네... 거기다 진통제도
많이 복용했거든요
That and half a dozen
painkillers.
That's not
a good combination.
훌륭한 조합은 아니네요
No, apparently not.
네, 그런 거 같아요
Don't worry.
Nothing happened.
걱정하지 마요
아무 일도 없었어요
How did I get here, then?
어쩌다 여기까지
오게 됐죠?
몸을 잘못 가누길래
집에 데려다 주려고 했는데
You were
a little bit wobbly.
I tried to take you home,
당신이 절대 보여주고
싶지 않다고 했어요
but you became very adamant
about me not seeing it.
You are married, yes?
결혼했군요?
아뇨
No.
그럼 동거인이
있나 보죠?
You live
with someone, then?
No.
아뇨
Um, where are my pants?
제 바지는 어딨어요?
당신이 직접 벗었어요
You took them off yourself.
말했듯이, 얼마든지
머물러도 돼요
Like I said,
stay as long as you like.
Just, uh, do me a favor
다만 나갈 때
잠가둘 수 있게
and tell the doorman downstairs
that you're leaving,
아래층 경비원에게
말이나 전해줘요
so he can lock up.
Okay.
알았어요
그 오믈렛이
숙취에 좋을 거예요
And eat the omelet.
It's good for the hangover.
Adios.
그럼 이만
How was dinner last night?
어제 저녁은 어땠어?
문어요리가 훌륭하다고
들었는데
I hear the octopus
is sensational.
이걸 어떻게...
How did you--
Our friends at the C.N.I.
took this.
CNI의 우리 친구가
찍은 거야
You realize operatives
are not permitted
요원들은 외국인과 사귀면
안 되는 건 알고 있지?
to date foreigners,
don't you?
보시는 것과는 달라요
I--this is not
what it looks like.
게다가 왜 스페인 정보국이
절 미행한 거죠?
And why is Spanish intelligence
following me?
네가 아니라
저 남자였어
They weren't.
They were following him.
자비에르 에차르떼
Zavier Etxarte.
Why?
He's a chef.
요리사를 왜요?
과거엔 ETA 조직원이었어, 애니
바스크 분리주의자 말이야
He's a former member
of the E.T.A., Annie--
a Basque separatist.
테러리스트로 의심되는 자들과
아직도 교류 중이지
And he's still in contact
with suspected terrorists.
Terrorists?
Zavier?
자비에르가
테러리스트라고요?
You wanted to know
what's next?
다음 임무는 뭐냐고
했었지? 이거야
Well, this is it.
Zavier is your new op.
자비에르가
네 새 임무야
It's a tale of two brothers.
Zavier and Gorka Etxarte.
이건 두 형제에
관한 이야기야
자비에르와 고르카
에차르떼 형제
둘은 열여덟, 열여섯 때 함께
"자유조국바스크"에 가담했어
They joined
the Euskadi Ta Askatasuna
together at the ages
of 18 and 16 respectively.
In 2003, a cell
of ETA terrorists
2003년에 지방 정부 공무원의
납치와 관련돼서
was rounded up in connection
with the kidnapping
ETA의 테러
세포 조직이 체포됐죠
of a provincial government
official.
고르카는 살인 공모죄로
유죄를 선고받았습니다
Gorka was convicted
of conspiracy to commit murder.
Zavier was arrested
but never charged.
자비에르도 체포됐지만
기소되진 않았어
He emigrated
to the states in 2005,
2005년에 미국으로
이민 와서
found his new calling
in the kitchen,
요리사로 새로운
경력을 쌓다가
and decided to open
his own restaurant here in D.C.
한 달 전에 워싱턴에
자기 식당을 개업하기로 했어
just one month ago.
스페인 대사관과
겨우 두 블록 떨어져 있죠
And just two blocks away
from the Spanish embassy.
Precisely.
정확해, CNI도 그래서
그곳을 택했다고 믿고 있어
C.N.I. believe that's exactly
why he chose that location.
고르카는요?
- What about Gorka?
- That's kind of why we're here.
우리가 모인 이유가
바로 그거야
고르카는 3주 전
석방됐습니다
Gorka was released from prison
three weeks ago.
C.N.I. has been monitoring
his activities in Bilbao.
CNI는 빌바오에서
그의 활동을 감시하고 있죠
ETA는 무력을 서슴지
않고 사용하는데
ETA's never been shy
about calling their shots.
대사관에 들어온
협박은 없나요?
Has the embassy received
any threats?
아니, 하지만 바스크
군인의 날 기념식이
No, but Basque Soldier's Day
is being commemorated
later this week.
이번 주말이야
역사적으로 폭력적 활동이
증가한 기간이죠
Historically,
the Spanish have seen
an uptick
in violent activity.
ETA는 무장 투쟁 포기를
선언하지 않았나요?
I thought ETA declared
a permanent cease-fire.
맞아요, 지난 10년간
세 번씩이나 선언했죠
Yep, for the third time
this decade.
오기, 자비에르의 식당을
조사할 팀을 꾸려줘
Auggie, I want you
to put together a team
to sift through
Zavier's restaurant--
종업원이나 공급업자
손님, 투자자들 전부 조사해
his employees, his purveyors,
his customers, and investors.
Follow the money,
and don't even think about lunch
자금을 추적하고
현황 보고 하기 전까지
점심은 꿈도 꾸지 마
until I get a status report.
점심이요? 브런치 전에
가져다 드리죠
Lunch?
You'll have it by brunch.
애니는 자비에르에게
가까이 접근해서
Annie, I want you
to stick close to Zavier.
See what, if anything,
pops up,
적어도 기념일 기간의
특이 사항을 관찰해
at least
through the holiday.
Uh, Joan, I'm sorry,
but, uh--
조안, 죄송합니다만
You know,
that's not what I like to hear
지시 내린 다음에
그런 말 듣긴 참 싫던데
after giving a directive.
그건 알고 있습니다만...
I realize that.
However, um...
I just wasn't clear
about the directive.
자비에르에게 접근하란 말의
뜻을 정확히 모르겠어요
"Stick close to Zavier"?
He works, like, 30 hours a day
in a really busy restaurant.
붐비는 식당에서 하루에
서른 시간은 일해서
아주 늦은 시간 아니면
만날 수도 없어요
The only time I could see him
would be late, late at night.
So what's the problem?
그래서 뭐가 문제지?
The problem is...
문제는...
You know, Latin men.
아시잖아요
라틴 남자들이 어떤지...
Not as well as you do,
apparently.
너만큼은
잘 모르겠는데?
If I go back
to see him tonight,
제가 오늘
또 만나러 가면
자기랑 자고 싶어한다고
생각할 거예요
he's going to assume
I intend to sleep with him.
Let's be perfectly clear.
확실하게 말해둘게
너한테 누구와 자라는
명령이 아니야
I'm not asking you
to sleep with anyone.
잠재적 위협에 접근해서
그 위협을 평가하란 거지
I'm asking you to locate
and assess a potential threat.
How you do that
is up to you.
그 방법은...
너한테 달린 거지
래리, 자리 좀 비켜주겠나?
Larry, do you mind?
I need a little bonding time
with my son here.
아들과 친목의 시간을
가져야겠군
You can't possibly be
this obtuse.
넌 어떻게 이렇게까지
둔할 수가 있냐?
Dad, I really don't want
to talk about this here.
- 얘기하고 싶지 않아요
- 내가 직접?
You ask--
ask to be deposed?
직접 나서서
증언하겠다고?
How could you know that?
어떻게 아셨죠?
휘파람 살짝 분다고
Do you think
blowing your little whistle
기관에서 널
알아줄 거라 믿어?
is gonna gain you favor
in the Agency?
오늘 네 정직성과
청렴을 칭찬하며
The people
slapping your back today
for being so honest
and forthright
네 등을 두드려줄
사람들은
will be the same ones
who won't share
너와는 어떠한 정보도
공유하지 않을 거다
another piece
of information with you
because they know now
you like to talk.
넌 입이 가볍다는 걸
알아버렸으니까
I didn't expect you
to understand.
아버지의 이해는
기대하지 않아요
그렇겠지
I get it.
You're frustrated.
좌절스럽겠지
Arthur shut you out,
아서가 널 내쳤고
아비가 널 챙겨줄 위치에
아직 오르지 못했으니까
and I'm not in position yet
to be there for you.
- If you can just sit tight...
- Come on.
- 잠자코 기다리면...
- 그만 하세요
For a little more time,
it's all going to work out.
조금만 더 기다리면
다 해결할 수 있어
But if you finger me
as the leak--
하지만 날 누설자로
지목한다면
저라고 이러고
싶은 줄 아세요?
You think I want to do this...
to my own father?
자기 아버지를?
Don't put yourself
in that position, son.
나서지 말고
조용히 있으렴, 아들아
제겐 다른 선택이 없어요
I don't have a choice.
Our national security
has been compromised.
국가 안보가
위험에 처해있는데
I'm just trying to do my part
to repair the breach...
그걸 막는 제 역할에
충실하고 싶은 것뿐이에요
For my country
and my conscience.
제 조국과
제 양심을 위해서요
조국과 양심?
For your country
and conscience?
Who talks like that?
도대체 누가
그런 소릴 하냐?
Did you not learn
anything from me?
아비한테서 배운 게
그렇게도 없어?
I guess not.
그런가 보네요
It's hard
to believe sometimes
가끔 믿기
힘들 때가 있단다
you're actually
my son.
네가 정말로
내 아들이란 사실이
I'm warning you,
I'm no Julia Child.
경고하는데
난 요리 잘 못해요
You don't have to be
for this.
그렇게 어렵지
않은 거예요
달걀 요리 비법 알려줘서
다시 한번 고마워요
Thanks again for showing me
how to make the eggs.
배우고 싶은 마음이 간절하겠죠
나도 이해해요
You had a craving.
I understand.
I'm not keeping you
from anything, am I?
내가 방해되는 건 아니죠?
At 1:00 in the morning, no.
새벽 1시엔 아니죠
내일 아침에 마저 하지
이제 당신 전담이에요
I'm all yours.
- That's it?
- That's it.
- 끝이에요?
- 맞아요
Now we just need
to figure out
이제 30분을 보낼
방법을 찾으면 돼요
how to kill
half an hour.
What's this?
그건 뭐죠?
내 커다란 실수를
가려주는 거예요
This is me
covering up a big mistake.
어렸을 때
잘못된 결정을 했죠
I made some bad decisions
when I was young.
얼마나 잘못된
결정이었죠?
How bad?
대가로 1년의 자유가
필요한 정도였죠
Bad enough to co me
a year of freedom.
That's where I learned
how to cook, actually...
사실 그곳에서
요리를 배웠어요
감옥에서요
In prison.
지금이라도 겁에 질려
도망쳐도 괜찮아요
You can run away in horror now,
if you like.
I understand.
이해해요
No.
I'm okay.
아니에요
난 괜찮아요
그점을 요리사를 하면서
가장 좋아해요
That's what I like most
about being a chef.
Every day I get to make
a thousand small decisions--
날마다 수천 가지
작은 결정을 내린다는 점이요
what pan to use, how much salt,
how much flame.
어떤 팬을 쓸까?
소금의 양은?
불의 강도는?
And I can make
the right ones.
난 옳은 결정을
내릴 수 있죠
I can actually taste
when I make the right decision.
옳은 결정을 내렸을 때
실제로 그 맛을
느낄 수도 있어요
한 가지로는 과거의 일을
되갚진 못하겠지만
Alone, none of them
can make up for the past.
But all together,
it's a start.
그 모든 옳은 결정들이
출발점이 될 거예요
I forgot something.
하나 깜빡했네요
Not the Izarra.
설마 이자라는 아니겠죠
No, uh, creme fraiche.
아뇨...
생크림이요
I'll be right back.
금방 돌아올게요
Oh!
I didn't know
you had company.
사람이 와 있는 줄 몰랐네
Uh, Annie,
this is my--
애니, 이쪽은 제...
Juan, an old friend.
후안입니다
오래된 친구죠
Hola.
I'm Annie.
안녕하세요
애니예요
Hi.
So nice to meet you.
만나서 반갑습니다
잔이 더 필요하군요
오랜만의 재회를...
So I should get another glass.
We're celebrating...
Old acquaintances
and, uh, new friends.
축하하려 했는데
- 새 친구도 좋죠
- 아뇨, 괜찮아요
No.
No, no, that's okay.
아뇨, 카탈로니아산(産)
카바를 몇 상자 가져왔는데
No, you should try it.
I brought a couple of cases.
It's Cava from Catalonia.
It's really, really nice.
정말 훌륭하답니다
맘에 드실 거예요
You'd like it.
Uh, you know, I should leave
you guys alone to catch up.
두 분 시간 보내시게
저는 이만 가볼게요
I think that's a good idea.
그편이 낫겠네요
No, no. You shouldn't,
uh, not on my account.
아뇨, 아뇨
저 때문에 가지 마세요
Any friend of Zavier
is a friend of mine.
자비에르의 친구는
제 친구이기도 하니까요
이렇게 예쁜 아가씨를
왜 몰아내려는 거야?
동생하고
시간 좀 보내려고 그런다
내가 너무 오랫동안
감옥에서 썩어서 말이야
형이 이 여자한테
관심 없다면...
요리마저 못 해서
미안하게 됐어요
I'm sorry
for the interruption.
But, uh,
get your purse,
그래도...
지갑 챙기시고
and we can continue this lesson
some other time?
레슨은 다음에
마저 할까요?
Of course.
Bye, Juan.
좋아요
또 봬요, 후안
So nice to meet you.
Vaya con dios, Annie.
반가웠습니다
축복이 함께 하시길, 애니
감옥에서 출소했다던
동생 있죠? / 네
The brother who just
got out of jail...
- Yeah?
- He's not in Bilbao anymore.
이젠 빌바오에
있는 게 아니에요
잘 잤어요?
안전 가옥은 어때요?
Hello, Sunshine.
How's the safe house?
Feeling safe?
안전한 느낌이에요?
왜 아무도
대학 시절 빼곤
I now know why nobody sleeps
on a futon after college.
요 깔고 자지 않는지
이젠 알겠어요
Rough night's sleep, huh?
잠을 설쳤군요?
I started making a list
of the things I realize I need.
필요한 물건들
목록을 만들어야겠어요
I need a bed.
I need a microwave.
침대도 필요하고
전자레인지도 필요하고
And I need a bottle opener.
병따개도 필요해요
I really need
a bottle opener.
병따개는 정말이지
절실해요
You definitely need
a bottle opener.
병따개는 필수품목이죠
Where are we at
with Gorka?
고르카에 관한 건요?
진전을 보이고 있어요
두 형제가 어젯밤
Well, we're making progress.
Garcia trailed
the brothers back to
Zavier's apartment last night.
자비에르의 아파트에 가는 걸
가르시아가 추적했죠
Zavier left at 5:30
for the produce market.
자비에르는 5시 반에
농수산물 시장에 갔고
고르카는 10여분 전에
Gorka set off
about ten minutes ago
with two unidentified men
of Spanish origin.
스페인계 신원미상자
두 명과 함께 떠났어요
And it appears that
they're casing the embassy
대사관과 가능한 탈출 경로를
정찰하는 게 분명해요
and possible escape routes.
Did, uh, Gorka
have his bag with him?
고르카가 자기 가방도
가지고 갔나요?
What bag?
무슨 가방이요?
Gorka had a duffel bag
when he came
어젯밤 식당에 왔을 때
더플 백을 가지고 있었어요
into the restaurant last night.
Is it on him?
가지고 있나요?
잠깐 기다려요
Hold on a second.
He does not have the bag
with him in the car.
차에 가방을 가지고
타진 않았네요
I bet it's
in Zavier's apartment.
분명 자비에르의
아파트에 있을 거예요
Okay. I'm setting up
a cleaning crew
알았어요
조사팀을 투입해서
to go in
and search for it now.
바로 찾아볼게요
I can do it.
I know the layout.
내가 할 수 있어요
아파트 구조도 알아요
No.
That is a negatory, Annie.
안 돼요
그건 반대예요, 애니
That is
too compromising.
너무 위험해요
I-I'm five minutes out,
and I have a way in.
5분이면 나갈 수 있고
들어갈 방법도 있어요
Do you have a better plan?
더 나은 방법이라도
있어요?
You remember me
from the other day?
지난 번에 왔었는데
저 기억하세요?
- Mm-hmm.
- Good.
좋아요
선생님의 도움이
정말 필요해요
Listen, I could really use
your help with something.
I need to get
into Mr. Etxarte's apartment.
에차르떼 씨 아파트에
들어갈 일이 있거든요?
Uh, you can call Mr. Z
and have him give me the okay.
먼저 전화해서
괜찮은지 여쭤보시죠?
It's kind of embarrassing,
actually.
사실 좀 난감한
상황인데요
I left my ring upstairs...
제 반지를 두고
나왔거든요
남편이 결혼할 때 준
그 반지 말이에요
The ring my husband gave me
when we got married.
- Here you go.
- I will just be a minute.
- 됐습니다
- 금방 찾을게요
Uh, no.
I'm coming in with you too.
그건 안 되죠
제가 함께 있겠습니다
Oh, Mr. Vahidi,
could you help me, please?
배히디 씨?
좀 도와주시겠어요?
My cable's out again.
케이블이 또 나갔어요
I'll be right back.
금방 돌아오겠습니다
Oh.
Hey, Gus.
Hi!
어머, 거스
안녕?
That's a good boy.
착하지
I'm in.
Roger that.
- 들어왔어요
- 좋아요
빠져나오기 전까지
통화 유지해요
Stay on the line until
you clear out of there.
Annie, I need you
to wrap things up in there.
애니, 그만 마무리해요
알았어요, 잠깐만요
거의 다 끝났어요
Okay, just a second.
I'm almost finished.
고르카를
시야에서 놓쳤어요
We lost our visual
on Gorka.
I found it--
방금 찾았...
안녕하세요
Hi.
Annie, right?
- 애니 맞죠?
- 네
Right.
What are you doing here,
Annie?
여긴 어쩐 일이죠, 애니?
반지를 놓고 갔는데...
I forgot my ring,
but I found it.
방금 찾았어요
Does Zavier know
you're here?
여기 온 걸
자비에르도 아나요?
I didn't want
to bother him.
방해하기 싫어서요
Yes, Zavier doesn't like
to be bothered,
그렇죠, 자비에르는
방해받는 걸 싫어하니...
so it would probably
be best like this.
- 이게 최선이었겠죠
- 너무 난처하네요
It's embarrassing enough.
I should probably go.
이만 가볼게요
Have we met before,
Annie?
우리 전에 만난 적
있던가요, 애니?
- Before last night?
No, I don't--
어젯밤 말고요? 아뇨...
그런 거 같지 않네요
I don't think so.
I felt the same,
저도 그렇게
느꼈었는데
당신 얼굴을 얼핏
본 것도 같더군요
but then I saw this flash
of recognition in your face.
Was I mistaken?
잘못된 건가요?
아뇨, 그냥 뭐...
No, it's just, um...
저도 당신 닮은
친구가 있어요
You look like
a friend of mine.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
그래요?
Zavier mentioned you just
moved into the neighborhood.
근처로 이사왔다고
자비에르가 그러더군요
- Is that right?
- Yeah.
- 맞나요?
- 네
I hear it's a pretty
dangerous neighborhood.
여기는 제법 위험한
동네라고 들었습니다만
Sorry about that.
죄송하게 됐습니다
무슨 일이죠?
당신은 누구야?
What's going on here?
Who are you?
- Any word on Gorka yet?
- Disappeared again.
- 고르카에 소식은요?
- 또 사라졌어요
I think he may be part vapor.
'증발'하는 법을
아는 거 같아요
그건 그렇고
당신이 찾은 사진은
The pictures you found,
by the way,
모두의 관심을
불러일으켰죠
piqued everyone's interest.
에두아르도 리에라 캄피오
"Eduardo Riera Campillo."
Vice consul
of the Spanish embassy.
스페인 대사관의
부영사인데
한때는 마드리드의
연방 법정에서
And once upon a time,
he was a Magistrate
with the Audiencia Nacional
in Madrid.
치안판사로 근무했어요
Let me guess.
He ruled against Gorka's appeal.
아마도 고르카의 항소를
기각한 판사겠죠?
Even better.
He refused to hear it.
그보다 더해요, 신청을
받아들이지도 않았어요
CNI는 부영사를 임시로
안전 가옥에 피신시켰고
C.N.I. is moving him
into a safe house temporarily,
and they've begun to discreetly
evacuate the embassy.
조심스럽게 대사관을
대피 작업을 시작했죠
And what about Zavier?
자비에르에 관한 건요?
He hasn't left the restaurant
시장에서 돌아온 뒤론
식당을 떠나지 않았어요
since he got back
from the market.
조안은 나보고
다시 가보래요?
Does Joan want me
to go back in?
모르겠네요
현재는 주체는 FBI예요
Don't know.
FBI is on point now.
Permission requested
to read in Zavier Etxarte
자비에르를 CIA 정보원으로
포섭하는 일을 허가해주세요
as a CIA asset.
No.
안 돼
Why not?
왜 안 되죠?
Because there's
a strong possibility
여전히 테러 세포 조직에서
활동하고 있을 가능성이 높고
he's still an active member
of a terrorist cell,
최소한 요주의 인물에게
은신처를 제공하긴 하니까
and at the very least,
he's been harboring
a potentially dangerous
person of interest.
He let his brother sleep
on his couch.
자기 동생을 소파에
재워준 거죠
테러리스트라고 하기엔
잃을 게 너무 많아요
Zavier's not a terrorist.
He has too much to lose.
안 지 얼마나 됐지?
이틀?
And you've known him
for how long--two days?
Assets need to be vetted
much more fully.
정보원에겐 훨씬 더
많은 조사가 필요해
We might not have
enough time.
시간이 불충분할지도 몰라요
Because this is rapidly
becoming a criminal matter,
범죄 관련 사항이
됐기 때문에
FBI에 관할권을
넘겨줄 생각이야
I'm gonna let the Bureau
handle it from here.
최근의 제 일에 실망하셨다면
직접 말씀해주세요
If you've been disappointed
with my performance lately,
I wish you'd come out
and tell me.
What are you talking about?
무슨 소리야?
제가 돌아온 뒤로 계속
절 무시하고 계시잖아요
You've been dismissive
ever since I came back.
- Annie--
- And you've run roughshod
자비에르에 관한 제 평가는
전부 가차 없이 반대하시고요
over every objection
I've had regarding Zavier.
말 계속 잇기 전에
Before you continue,
I'd advise you to consider
조직에서 우리 둘의 지위를
고려해달라고 충고할게
where each of us rank in the
hierarchy of this organization.
I'm sorry.
죄송해요
I don't mean to be
disrespectful.
무례를 범할
생각은 아니었어요
You're feeling down,
and you're beating yourself up.
넌 낙심했고
자책하고 있어
And that's okay.
그건 괜찮아, 네가
이겨낼 거라 믿으니까
I'm confident
you can work through this.
하지만 자비에르를
포섭하는 일이
But reading in Zavier
is not gonna make up
봉투를 분실한 거나
for you losing that package
네 언니와의 일을
되갚을 순 없어
or for how things went
with your sister.
This has nothing to do
with my sister.
언니하고는
아무 상관 없어요
Are you sure about that?
확실해?
- 윌콕스 씨?
- 네
- Mr. Wilcox.
- Yes.
Could you come with me,
please?
같이 가주시겠습니까?
The D.N.I. would like
to talk with you.
국가정보국장님이
당신을 찾으십니다
Uh, could we schedule it
for later?
나중으로 미룰 수 있을까요?
참석할 회의가 있어서요
I have a meeting
to get to.
의회 증언이요
잘 알고 있습니다
Your deposition on the hill--
we know already.
The D.N.I. would like
a brief word beforehand.
국장님께서 사전에
만났으면 하십니다
Hello?
아무도 없어요?
자비에르?
Zavier?
Annie!
Hello.
애니!
안녕하세요
고기를 손질하고
있었어요
I was just butchering
some meat.
- Hey.
- Um...
반가워요
We are the masters
of bad timing, aren't we?
우린 시간 잘못 잡는 덴
뭔가 있는 것 같네요
Are you closed for lunch?
점심 시간 때문에
문 닫은 거예요?
매주 월요일은
쉬는 날이에요
On Mondays, yes,
I'm closed all day.
그래도 식당에 나와서
메뉴를 구상하죠
But I like to come in by myself
to think about the menu.
You know?
동생이 어디 있는지
알아야겠어요
I need to find
your brother.
고르카가 어디
있는지 알아요?
Do you know
where Gorka is?
I know he's your brother,
Zavier.
동생이란 거 알아요
어디 있는지 찾아야 해요
I need to find him.
Why do you need to find him?
Who are you?
왜 찾아야 한다는 거죠?
당신 누구예요?
Are you with the FBI?
FBI예요?
자세한 건 말해줄 수 없지만
날 믿어줘요
I can't give you all
the Details, but trust me.
저와 협력하는데
결국엔 당신에게
Cooperating with me will be
better for you in the end
다른 무엇보다도
좋은 선택이 될 거예요
than every other
alternative!
왜 동생이 워싱턴에
왔는지는 알아요?
Do you even know
why he's here in D.C.?
당신네 정부 깡패들은
늘 이런 식이죠, 안 그래요?
You government goons are
really all the same, aren't you?
He served
his sentence already.
고르카는 이미
죗값을 치렀어요
Do you understand that?
모르겠어요?
내 동생을 평생토록
추적할 권리 따위 없다고요!
You have no right
to hunt him down forever!
Zavier--
- 자비에르...
- 몇 번의 웃음과
A couple of laughs
and a little sleepover,
내 집에서
살짝 자고 간 걸로
and you now expect me
to betray my brother?
내가 동생을 배반할 거라
예상했어요?
My brother?
내 동생을?
옳은 일을 해주길
부탁하는 거예요
I'm asking you
to do the right thing.
내 식당에서 나가요
Get out of my restaurant...
Now.
당장
Yeah.
- 네
- 애니, 지금 어디예요?
Annie, where are you
right now?
에차르떼 근처예요
왜요?
Etxarte, kind of.
Why?
고르카 일당이 숨어 있던
은신처에 대한
We got a tip on the safe house
Gorka's guys were holing up in.
제보가 들어왔어요
FBI가 도착하기 전에
이미 달아났는데
Before the FBI could get there,
the place had been vacated.
But they found traces
of ammonium nitrate prills
FBI가 그곳에서
질산 암모늄 프릴의
과산화 아세톤 분말의
흔적을 찾아냈어요
and acetone peroxide powder.
TATP요?
T.A.T.P.?
폭탄을 만들고
있던 거예요, 애니
They were building
a bomb, Annie.
Did they find any, uh,
champagne bottles?
FBI가 발견한 것 중에
샴페인 병은 없었나요?
What?
- 네?
- 카바 병이나 라벨이요
Cava bottles
o-or labels?
Yes.
있어요
고르카가 준 카바 상자요
그거 어떻게 했죠?
The cases of cava
that Gorka brought you--
what did you do with them?
- They're behind the bar.
바 뒤편에 있어요
나가라고 했을 텐데요?
I thought I told you
to get out.
지금 뭐하는 거죠?
What do you think
you're doing?
이젠 내 물건을
뒤지는 거예요?
You're going through
my things now?
정말 어이가 없군요
This is ridiculous.
I think you're paranoid.
당신은 편집증이
심한 거 같네요
Okay.
찾았어요
Uh...
Go.
뛰어요
Oh!
그래...
어떻게 된 거죠?
So what happened?
Did you forget everything
the farm taught you
훈련소에서 배운
뇌관 제거법은 잊었어요?
about defusing a bomb?
I did...
맞아요
사실은 빨간 불이
깜빡이는 걸 본 순간
Actually, when I saw that little
red light blinking, and, uh...
이론과 실전 사이의
거대한 차이를 느꼈죠
There's big gap
between theory and practice.
운이 좋아요
사상자가 없으니까요
Well, we got lucky--
no casualties.
We're gonna spin it
as a gas-leak explosion.
가스 누출 사고였다고
꾸밀 거예요
아마 폭탄이었단 말보단
안전하게 들리겠죠
Supposedly sounds safer
than a bomb--I don't know.
고르카는 아직도
못 찾았어요? / 네
- Did they find Gorka yet?
- No.
자비에르는 어떻게
되는 거죠?
What's gonna happen to Zavier?
We got to find him first.
우선은 찾아야겠지만
더는 용의자로 보진
않을 거 같네요
Pretty sure he's not going
to be a suspect anymore.
여기가 자비에르의
모든 것이었는데
This was his whole life.
Well, on the bright side,
긍정적인 면을 보자면
당신 언니는 당신에게
폭탄은 안 쓴다는 거죠
at least your sibling's
not trying to blow you up.
No.
그렇죠
언니는 천천히
태워 죽이는 쪽이죠
She prefers a slower burn.
언니 집에 일찍 들르지
못할 경우를 대비해서
Well, in case
you can't get home so fast,
안전 가옥 집들이
선물을 지금 줄게요
here's
a safe-housewarming gift.
You can use it to pop your top
whenever the mood strikes you.
우울한 기분이 들면
이걸로 터뜨리도록 해요
Bottle opener--
cool.
병따개네요
멋져라
If you want to practice,
연습하고 싶으면 지금
앨런스 펍에 가도 되는데요
we can go to Allen's
right now.
Thank you.
But what I want right now
제안은 고맙지만
지금은
is peace and quiet
and a hot, hot bath.
조용하고 평화롭게
목욕이나 하고 싶어요
더구나 모퉁이 돌면
바로 내 안전 가옥이에요
Besides, my safe house is right
around the corner.
Oh, come on, Annie.
You know the rules.
안 돼요, 애니
규칙 알잖아요
알아요, 어딘지 누구한테도
말하면 안 된다는 거요
I know. I'm not supposed
to tell anybody
where my safe house is.
Even you?
- 당신한테도요?
- 맞아요, 나한테도요
That's right--even me.
I'm going there right now,
그럼 난 이제 가볼 텐데
어디 있는지 모르고 싶다면
so, if you don't want to know
where it is,
you better close your eyes.
눈 감고 있는 편이
좋을 거예요
Hey!
이봐!
Really?
이러기야?
You no-show the deposition?
증언 시간에
안 나타나?
- I tried to reach you.
- Two hours after the fact.
- 연락하려고 했어
- 두 시간 지나서 말이지
Do you want to take
a guess
한번 맞혀볼래?
오늘 내가 얼마나
바보 꼴이 됐는지?
how much of a moron
I looked like today?
You?
What about me?
네가?
나는 어떻고?
난 건물을 나서는 길에
I'm on my way
out of the building,
국가정보국장실로
끌려갔어
and I get yanked
into the D.N.I.'s office.
도대체 국장이
어떻게 안 거야?
How the hell did he know
I was coming in?
그럼 무슨 소리야?
내가 누설했다고?
So what are you saying?
What, that I leaked?
누군가는 했지
Well, somebody did.
침묵하라고 얼마나
거대한 압박을 받았는지
You have no idea how
much pressure they put on you
넌 짐작도 못할 거야
to keep quiet.
지금 이 자리에서
네 소환장을 발부할 수도 있어
You know I can slap
a subpoena on you right here.
해봐
Do it.
"기억이 안 난다"로
초지일관할 테니까
I will "I do not recall" you
to death.
네게 아무 말도
안 했다고 하겠어
I'll deny
I told you anything.
They're gonna have my ass
on this.
윗선에서 날
들들 볶을 거야
신세는 갚을게, 캠
약속하지
I'm gonna make this up
to you, Cam. I promise.
I've played enough poker
with you, Jai,
그동안의 포커 게임으로
네 거짓말 정돈 눈치챌 수 있어
to know when you're lying.
I just can't figure out why.
그 이유를
모를 뿐이지
Shh, shh, shh, shh,
shh, shh, shh.
I told you
it was a bad neighborhood.
위험한 동네라고
했을 텐데?
같이 걷지
Come, let's walk.
Don't do anything
stupid now.
어리석은 짓 하지 마
타
우리가 돌아가면
모든 걸 바꾸는 거야
다시는 안 해
굽실거리는 짓은
이제 신물 나
What are you doing?
Where are we going?
당신 누구예요?
어디로 가는 거죠?
Well, you are
our insurance policy.
당신은 우리의
보험이라고 할 수 있지
인질을 데리고 있는 건
늘 도움이 되거든
You see, it always helps
to have a hostage...
In case things
don't go as planned.
일이 계획대로
되지 않았을 때 말이야
Now, a female CIA Agent?
그런데 CIA의
여성 요원이라?
That's just, you know,
fantastic.
그건 정말이지...
환상적이지
무슨 소릴
하는지 모르겠네요
I don't know what
you're talking about.
부정할 생각이야?
Are you really going to
try to deny it?
나한테 당신이
어떻게 보이는지 알아?
You know what
you look like to me?
You look like a girl that's been
strapped to a car door before.
차 문에 묶여본 경험이
있는 여자로 보여
뭐랄까, 당신은
너무나 침착해
The thing is,
you're way too cool.
There you go. There you go.
그렇지, 바로 그거야
That's the spirit.
어떻게 되나 보게
창문도 한번 걷어차 봐
Kick the window.
See what happens.
You know,
the restaurant was closed.
식당은 오늘
휴점이었어요
Nobody was there
but Zavier.
자비에르밖에 없었죠
자비에르가
식당에 있었어?
Zavier was
in the restaurant?
폭발하기 전에
내가 데리고 나왔어요
I got him out
before it blew.
목표가 누구였는진
모르겠지만
I don't know
who your target was,
but no one suffered,
not even a scratch.
아무도 다친 사람 없어요
상처 하나 없었죠
이런 경이적인 실패의
소감이 어때요?
How does it feel to fail
so spectacularly?
실패라곤
누가 그래?
Who said I failed?
내 목표는
식당이 전부였어
The restaurant was
my only target.
모든 변절자들에게
보내는 메시지였지
It's a message
to all the quemados.
넌 우리 조직을
위험에 빠뜨렸고
You jeopardize
our cause,
and you will be held
accountable.
그 책임을 지게 될 거야
당신의 형은...
But your brother was--
혼자만 살겠다고
날 저버린 순간부터
Zavier stopped being
my brother
the day he gave me up
to save his own neck.
자비에르는
내 형이 아니야
여기 있는 사람들이
내 형제들이지
These men right here...
They're my brothers.
It's bad enough he betrays me.
그 놈은 날 배신한 것도
모자라서
가족까지 배신한 놈이야
He betrays his family.
거기다 스페인 지배자들의
손을 핥아?
But licking the hand
of his Spanish masters?
"스프가 너무 뜨거운가요?
대사님?"
"Oh, is the soup too hot
for you, Mr. Ambassador?
"Maybe I should, uh,
blow on it
"제가 입으로 불어서
적당하게 식혀 드리죠"
just to get
the perfect temperature."
He's no better than a dog.
개보다 못한 놈이지
And he should know
what it feels like
자기가 사랑하는
모든 걸 잃은 기분을
to lose everything he loves.
형도 느껴봐야 해
넌 평생 하는 일이라곤
일을 엉망으로
망치는 것뿐이냐?
Aah!
Zavier!
자비에르!
난 새로운 삶을 시작했어!
우리 둘 모두를 위해!
I was starting a new life
for the both of us!
그걸 네가 전부
날려버렸어!
얼마나 받고
날 넘긴 거야?
그렇게 생각했어?
틀렸어, 고르카
그건 내가 아니었어
난 절대 형제를
배신하지 않아!
자비에르!
Zavier!
그만 해요!
Stop!
멈춰요, 자비에르!
그만둬요!
Stop, Zavier!
Stop!
계속해, 난 이미
죽은 목숨이야
가실 준비 됐나요
윌콕스 씨?
Are you ready to go,
Mr. Wilcox?
Yeah, I'm ready.
네, 준비됐습니다
특수 프로젝트 책임자
제이 윌콕스
Can I get you
a cup of coffee, sir?
커피라도 한 잔
가져다 드릴까요?
좋죠, 안 될 거 있나요
Yeah.
Why not?
Black, two sugars.
블랙에
설탕만 둘이요
Very good, sir.
알겠습니다
They say the office
makes the man.
직책이 사람을
만든다고들 하지
I truly hope
that is the case.
정말 그랬으면 좋겠구나
Hey, Dad.
아버지 오셨어요?
간단한 축하로
충분할 거 같은데요?
A simple "congratulations"
would suffice.
Three days ago,
you had one foot out the door,
사흘 전만 하더라도
그만두기 일보 직전이었는데
now you're majordomo
of a brand-new initiative,
지금은 국가정보국장에게
직속으로 보고하는
reporting directly
to the D.N.I.
최신 계획의
관리자가 됐구나
Bureaucracy has never worked
that fast before.
관료 체제 하에서
전에 없던 승진이지
It was a surprise to me
as well.
저도 놀랐어요
네 승진을 위해 얼마나 많은
연줄을 동원했는지 아니?
You know how many strings
I had to pull
to get you this promotion?
I can't imagine.
상상도 못하겠네요
All of them.
전부였어
That's how many.
그렇게나 많았다
네가 이렇게 낮은 지위였는지
미처 몰랐구나
I hadn't realized
just how low
your star had fallen
around here.
I'm a Wilcox,
for better or worse.
저도 좋든 싫든
윌콕스니까요
그야 당연하지
The hell you are.
넌 원칙이, 양심이
있다고 하지 않았었나?
You say you have a code,
a conscience?
이런 전망 좋은
사무실 하나면
Yet all it takes is
a room with a view
for you to chuck it away.
네 이상을 버리기에
충분했던 거지
이렇게 쉽게 흔들리느니
I'd rather you stand
on principle
원칙에 따라 날 늑대들에게
던져주는 게 나았을 거다
and feed me to the wolves
than waver so easily.
그러면 최소한 너에 대한
판단이라도 섰겠지
At least I'd know
the measure of you.
You are the most
selfish bastard I know.
아버지같이 이기적인
악당은 없을 거예요
All my life,
제 평생 아버지가
누군가를 위해
the only time you've ever
done anything for anyone
뭐라도 하는 경우는
is if it was
in your own self-interest.
아버지 자신의
이익이 걸려있을 때였죠
I needed to get out
from under Arthur's thumb.
전 아서의 손에서
벗어날 필요가 있었어요
I had to make sure that
you were properly motivated
아버지가 움직일 수밖에 없는
이유를 만들어야 했던 거죠
to pull your strings.
연줄을 동원하도록 말이죠
How did you know I'd get word
about your deposition?
내가 증언에 대해 알게 될 걸
어떻게 알았지?
I learned from the best.
전 최고한테서
배웠으니까요
You're playing
a dangerous game here, son.
넌 위험한 게임을
하고 있는 거다, 아들아
Keep it up.
계속하렴
I like it.
맘에 드는구나
Oh!
- Oh, sorry.
- I thought I heard you up here.
네가 와 있는 거 같아서
Um, I'm just
clearing out my stuff.
그냥 내 물건
정리하고 있었어
I got your message
the other night--don't worry.
전에 얘기했던 건
걱정하지 마
It's just gonna take me
a few trips.
몇 번 왔다갔다하면
될 거야
Okay, I'll leave you
to it, then.
그래, 그건
너한테 맡길게
Um, I--
내가...
I spent so much time and energy
그동안 내가
어떤 일을 하는지나
trying to tell you
why I did what I did
왜 하는지 말하려고
그렇게 애썼으면서도
that I never said
I'm sorry.
미안하다는 말을
안 했었어
And I'm sorry.
미안해
언니는 내 가족이자
내게 가장 소중한 친구야
You're my sister
and my best friend,
and you don't deserve to be
treated like that.
내가 언니에게
너무했다는 거 알아
If you can only carry
one box...
상자 하나만
들고 갈 거면
Take this one.
이걸 가져가
That's the stuff
you're really gonna need.
너한테 정말
필요한 물건일 거야
Thank you.
고마워
Mm-hmm. Yeah, and, uh,
you know about the...
그리고... 다른 상자들도
서두를 필요 없어
Other ones,
there's no rush.
I thought you were trying
to rent it out.
- 세놓는다고 했잖아?
- 맞아, 그런데...
Yeah. No, I am.
Um, but...
I'm--I'm not in a hurry.
서두르지 않으려고
It's hard to find
the right person.
적당한 사람을
찾는 일은 힘드니까
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♬ Hear the Noise That Moves
So Soft and Low ♬
James Vincent
애니에게
꼭 필요한 물건들
날 써!
피드백
whemie@gmail.com